

COMPLITER SCIENCE · RESEARCH ENGINEER · PH D. CANDIDATE

Institute of High Performance Computing (IHPC), A*STAR, 1 Fusionopolis Way, #16-16, Connexis North Tower, 138632, Singapore

□ (+65) 8590 6369 | Szhanq_hao@ihpc.a-star.edu.sq, hao@07@e.ntu.edu.sq | ★ isaacchanqhau.github.io | □ IsaacChanqhau | □ isaacchanqhau

Summary_

I am a research engineer at Artificial Intelligence Initiative (A*AI), **Agency for Science, Technology and Research (A*STAR)**. I have involved in several industrial/research projects in different directions, including visual grounding, natural language processing, commonsense knowledge graph and reinforcement learning for robotics.

Meanwhile, I am a part-time Ph.D. candidate at Data Management and Analytics Lab (DMAL), School of Computer Science and Engineering (SCSE), **Nanyang Technological University (NTU)**. My supervisor is Prof. **Aixin SUN** (NTU) and co-supervisor is Dr. **Joey Tianyi Zhou** (A*STAR). My primary research interests are *Natural Language Processing (NLP)* and *Machine Learning*. Currently, my research focuses on visual reasoning (*e.g.* vision-language tasks) and transfer learning for NLP (*e.g.* knowledge transfer for low-resource language).

Personal Email: 26hzhang AT gmail DOT com

Education _____

Nanyang Technological University (NTU)

50 Nanyang Avenue, SG 639798

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science

Aug 2019 - Present

Supervisor: Prof. Aixin SUN (NTU) · Co-supervisor: Dr. Joey Tianyi ZHOU (A*STAR)

Data Management and Analytics Lab (DMAL), School of Computer Science and Engineering (SCSE)

Nanyang Technological University (NTU)

50 Nanyang Avenue, SG 639798

M.Sc. in Communications Engineering

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE)

Dalian University of Technology (DUT)

Dalian City, P. R. China, 116024

B.Eng. in Communications Engineering

Sep 2011 - Jul 2015

School of Information and Communication Engineering (SICE)

Experience __

Artificial Intelligence Initiative (A*AI), A*STAR

1 Fusionopolis Way, SG 138632

RESEARCH ENGINEER

Jun 2018 - Present

• Human-Robot Collaborate AI for Advanced Manufacturing Engineering (AME) Project. The objective is to use planning, reinforcement learning and implicit learning techniques for concept grounding and human-interactive task learning to achieve efficient and easy-to-use Automatic Robotic Programming and Human-Robot Collaboration. I am responsible for the concept grounding and learning, which includes object detection, event localization, concept knowledge graph and vision-language learning.

Social & Cognitive Computing (SCC), A*STAR

1 Fusionopolis Way, SG 138632

RESEARCH ENGINEER

Jul 2016 - May 2018

- PrimeNet Project: Human-inspired Framework for Commonsense Knowledge Representation and Reasoning. The objective is to set out a framework for a commonsense knowledge base that allows for efficient processing, in order to meet the demands of commonsense reasoning and, hence, support intelligent machine performance in real-world tasks. At the same time, the PrimeNet still provide access to a vast knowledge resource of concepts involving specific object instances.
- MARACANA Project: Behavioural Understanding and Narrative Descriptions from Videos. The objective is to develop technology components that can analyze and narrate real world events captured in video, and provide the human user with a rapid understanding of the happenings in an environment. I am responsible for commonsense reasoning/learning, activity recognition in cognitive linguistic temporal-spatial representation and narrative scene description.

Selected Publications

First-Author Publication

(* indicates equal contribution)

[5] Span-based Localizing Network for Natural Language Video Localization

Hao Zhang, Aixin Sun, Wei Jing, Joey Tianyi Zhou

The 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2020.

[4] RoboCoDraw: Robotic Avatar Drawing with GAN-based Style Transfer and Time-efficient Path Optimization

Tianying Wang*, Wei Qi Toh*, **Hao Zhang***, Xiuchao Sui, Shaohua Li, Yong Liu, Wei Jing

Thirty-Forth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020.

[3] Dual Adversarial Transfer for Sequence Labeling

Joey Tianyi Zhou*, **Hao Zhang***, Di Jing, Xi Peng

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2019.

[2] Dual Adversarial Neural Transfer for Low-resource Named Entity Recognition

Joey Tianyi Zhou*, **Hao Zhang***, Di Jing, Hongyuan Zhu, Rick Siow Mong Goh, Kenneth Kwok The 57th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (**ACL**), 2019. (oral)

[1] RoSeq: Robust Sequence Labeling

Joey Tianyi Zhou*, **Hao Zhang***, Di Jing, Xi Peng, Yang Xiao, Zhiguo Cao IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (**TNNLS**), 2019.

Co-Author Publication

[3] Multi-source Meta Transfer for Low Resource Multiple Choice Question Answering

Ming Yan, **Hao Zhang**, Di Jin, Joey Tianyi Zhou

The 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2020.

[2] Efficient Robotic Task Generalization Using Deep Model Fusion Reinforcement Learning

Tianying Wang, **Hao Zhang**, Wei Qi Toh, Hongyuan Zhu, Cheston Tan, Yan Wu, Yong Liu, Wei Jing The IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (**ROBIO**), 2019.

[1] Learning With Annotation of Various Degrees

Joey Tianyi Zhou, Meng Fang, **Hao Zhang**, Chen Gong, Xi Peng, Zhiguo Cao, Rick Siow Mong Goh IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (**TNNLS**), 2019.

Theses

Removing Backscatter to Enhance the Visibility of Underwater Object

Supervisor: Lap Pui CHAU

Master of Science (M.Sc.), School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Nanyang Technological University

Research on an Improved Method for Image Enhancement Based on the Retinex Theory

Supervisor: Hongyu WANG

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), School of Information and Communication Engineering, Dalian University of Technology

Professional Services

- 2020 Technical Program Committee (TPC) Member, The EAI Mobile Multimedia Communications (MOBIMEDIA)
- 2019 **Program Committee (PC) Member**, The Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)

Honors & Awards

2019	Certificated, The Scientific Writing Skills Workshop Courses	Singapore
2018	1st Runner Up, Artificial Intelligence (AI) Hackathon in Agency for Science, Technology and Research	Singapore
2015	Outstanding Graduates, Dalian University of Technology	P. R. China
2013	Second Prize, Higher Education Press Cup College Student Mathematical Modeling Contest (National Level)	P. R. China
2013	First Prize, Higher Education Press Cup College Student Mathematical Modeling Contest (Provincial Level)	P. R. China
2013	Certificated, Undergraduate Innovation and Entrepreneurship Training Program (National Level)	P. R. China
2013	Second Prize, ACM/ICPC The Third Dalian City Programming Contest	P. R. China
2012, 2014 Learning Excellence Award (Second Prize), Dalian University of Technology		P. R. China
2012, 2013 Technological Innovation Award , Dalian University of Technology		P. R. China